Business Central makes analyzing and
working with your financial data simple
with integration to Microsoft Excel. You
can easily export data from a list page
to Excel and then analyze it using the
extensive data analysis tools Excel
provides. You can also edit your data in
Excel and then publish it back to
Business Central. Let's see how you can
quickly analyze Business Central data in
Excel. Let's say you want to create a
report from your customer ledger entries
that shows quarterly sales by customer.
On list pages, you have the option to
either open or edit in Excel. We'll open
the data in Excel for the web, but you
can also use the Excel app for Windows.
Once the data is open in Excel, we can
then use the application's powerful
reporting and charting functionality to
work with the data. We can view the
quarterly sales by customer we want to
see by creating a simple pivot table.
Choose to insert a pivot table from the
insert tab on the ribbon. We then have a
simple drag and drop experience for
creating the charts and graphs we
need to view sales. We can create a
filter for the table to view only the
posted invoices from the last quarter.
We can then do some quick data
formatting and make any other visual
changes we want. And we're done. This
gives us a table with all the
information we wanted to see. We can
also easily add a chart to visualize
this information. In a few clicks, we
can add a pivot chart to our report.
Analyzing the data in Excel enables
powerful reporting abilities, all of
which can be refreshed through the data
connection to ensure that the reports
and charts you create are always up to
date. Business Central also enables you
to easily update records in Excel. Let's
start on the customer's list page. We'll
assume we want to update the document
sending profile for all our customers.
This could take a while if you had to
update the field one by one on each
customer card. With edit in Excel, we
can make the changes we need and then
publish the changes back to Business
Central. When Excel opens, the Excel
addin pane displays. Here we can
refresh, filter, and publish our data.
The data is then imported from Business
Central.
Let's update the location code for all
our customers. We just need to make the
changes and then click on the publish
button. The data is now updated in
Business
Central. Once the changes have been
published successfully, we can then go
back to the customer card and see that
the field has been updated correctly for
all customers. The integration with
Microsoft Excel provides quick and
powerful data analytics as well as
simple options for updating your
data. Thank you for watching. We hope
you'll enjoy working with your business
central data in Excel.
[Music]